<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SwanseaCon 2018 - Agile Development &amp; Software Craftsmanship conference</title>
    <description>SwanseaCon is an agile development &amp; software craftsmanship conference</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Dave Stokes</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?*&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MySQL 8 Server Optimization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many folks run MySQL and the new version of MySQL has some big changes for the better. Hopefully my session will help uses exploit those new changes.  The new temporary file type and histograms will be a big win for many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully if they do not run MySQL they will know a little about relational databases.  For those that run MySQL I hope this will polish their knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first programming ex[erience was at Grossmont Community College in El Cajon CA (and I doubt any alumi will be joining me) in 1978.  Fortan on punch cards on a Digital Equipement Corporation KL 1091 36 bit computer.  And I started getting paid to work on computers not long after. And yes back then dinosaurs did roam the school parking lots which could prove very messy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is okay to say ‘I do not know; let me go explore’.  Too many feel guilty they do not know everything and do not admit they need to research.  Of course once you join the ranks of those of us who do know everything it makes you humble. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience is very sharp and it is always a joy to talk to a great audience.  That and Viv Richards keeps promissing to introduce me to Catherine Zeta-Jones when she comes to the conference.  Viv: Is she still planning on attending this year??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m here for the argument, How to build products people care about, and Questioning Requirements.  I generally recommend first time conferce attendees attend one session on a subjext they know zero about to expand their horizons.  That is if there is a hole in your schedule where there are no must attend sessions and that is often hard to do at Swanseacon.  And if you have questions for any speaker, please ask – even if it is before/after their talk as all the presenters love to sahre their knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Dave Stokes and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 16:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-dave-stokes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-dave-stokes</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SwanseaCon 2018 - Call for speakers is now open</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;swanseacon-2018---call-for-speakers-is-now-open&quot;&gt;SwanseaCon 2018 - Call for speakers is now open.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The call for speakers for the forth year of SwanseaCon is now open and will close on Friday 16th February 2018!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SwanseaCon is an agile development and software craftsmanship conference which is taking place on Monday September 10th 2018, at the Village Hotel, in Swansea, South Wales(UK).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you have never spoken at a conference, a relatively new speaker or spoken at many events - we want to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;speakers&quot;&gt;Speakers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re really pleased to announce that this years opening keynote will be by the fantastic Hadi Hariri (JetBrains), we will be announcing the closing keynote speaker very soon! We already have some speakers lined up including David Stokes (Oracle), Sander Hoogendoorn (DITISAGILE.NL), Kim Van Wilgen (ANVA), and Mashooq Badar (Codurance) - but we have lots more space and so we’re putting out a call for speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sessions&quot;&gt;Sessions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re happy for you to stand up and present a talk about your experiences or something you’ve done, but we also strongly encourage interactive sessions that generate conversation with the audience, group discussion, or hands-on experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the themes of the conference is agile development. If you work or have worked as part of an agile team to deliver software we’d love to hear from you. The other theme is software craftsmanship, it’s about well-crafted software, adding value to the software that you help to develop and deliver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we ask for talk submissions around agile development and software craftsmanship, below are just some of the talk titles that were submitted, accepted and run at previous SwanseaCon events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;swanseacon-2015-sessions&quot;&gt;SwanseaCon 2015 Sessions&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What Is Continuous Inspection, Anyway?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managing global teams : Lessons learned&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Level Up Your Tests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taking back BDD&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use your type system; write less code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scala in GOV.UK Digital Services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spreadsheets are Code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to use Theory of Constraints to scale big agile development teams?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software architecture vs code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It doesn’t work that way in enterprise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The differences between US and European startups from a technical leadership point-of-view.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lean UX and Agile development taking the Public sector to new levels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploring alternatives to software estimation with #NoEstimates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Refactoring mount doom: the story of a story&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common mistakes in TDD – can you guess?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bringing Agile Concepts to Operations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Legacy Code is Fear&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designing and building a micro-services architecture. Stairway to heaven or a highway to hell?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;swanseacon-2016&quot;&gt;SwanseaCon 2016&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s Do Kano Analysis of SwanseaCon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It doesn’t always have to be Scrum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introducing Eager Design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Toolset for Creating a Potentially Releasable Product Increment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seven ineffective coding habits many F# programmers don’t have&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Education for Engineers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From Scrum to Flow using Actionable Agile Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How deep are your tests?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tech Communities as Fandoms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How and Why to Love Cucumber&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User-Story Point estimation: a new approach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scaling MySQL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software Craftsmanship vs Lean Product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An Insider’s View Of Agile In The Public Sector&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;KISS me quick; The battle against complexity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organisational Wide Agility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Migration - from ‘Jurassic Park’ to MicroServices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SonarQube to manage our technical debt and increase value&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teal Organisations: A Living Example&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skills For Crafts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why so serious?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;swanseacon-2017-sessions&quot;&gt;SwanseaCon 2017 Sessions&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pair-Programming From a Beginner’s Perspective&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Harnessing Culture for Great Agile Relationships&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building a REPL for Phunkie, with Phunkie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Future is Serverless&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scaling Continuous Delivery is not black magic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serverless with Azure Functions - the rebel service&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scale @ Netflix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Domain-Driven Coding Architect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agile life lessons - looking beyond the processes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acceptance Testing on Mobile&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 things you need to know about BDD, Cucumber and SpecFlow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Defining MVP with Scenarios&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unit Tests: Let’s get skeptical&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘I am Groot’ - Learning Agile Testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building Empowered Teams at Scale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developing an agile mindset: leading teams to think beyond the tools, techniques and process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turning Development Outside–In&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The trouble with culture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Making Agile safe again: resisting the Borg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Test Driven Deployment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Branching strategies: choose wisely to minimise costs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Limiting WIP in the kitchen sink (aka ‘shamelessly capitalising upon an argument with my wife…’)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Live coding a chatbot in less than 15 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel guide to continuous delivery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motivation for You, your Craft, your Team and your Org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do have a talk that’s a bit different, please do not be put off - submit it or get in touch (hello@swanseacon.co.uk) and we can discuss it with you if you’d like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;attendees&quot;&gt;Attendees&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of our previous attendees have held the following positions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tester&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Professor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Entrepreneur&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apprentice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trainer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delivery Director&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software Architect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Business Analyst&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scrum Master&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Director of Digital Services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blogger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Product Owner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ready-to-submit&quot;&gt;Ready to submit?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would love you to submit! Please head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;www.swanseacon.co.uk/speaker-info&quot;&gt;call for speakers&lt;/a&gt; page and we will be in touch soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-more-advice-or-information&quot;&gt;For more advice or information&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope the above provides enough information about SwanseaCon and the types of sessions we are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your stuck or have any questions please get in touch. We’re happy to provide further advice if you need more help before submitting your session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email: hello@swanseacon.co.uk
Twitter: twitter.com/SwanseaCon&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 19:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/call-for-speakers-now-open</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/call-for-speakers-now-open</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keynote speakers for SwanseaCon 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re still busy going through all of the fantastic submissions we received from speakers wanting to be on the schedule for #SwanseaCon 2017. In the meantime we wanted to share with you the speakers who will be giving keynotes at this years event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sander Hoogendoorn will be returning for his third year at SwanseaCon and will be kicking things off on day one with the opening Keynote. The feedback the last two years on Sanders sessions has been fantastic with attendees stating he was one of the highlights of the event, and so we’re very pleased to be able to have him join us again. We will also be joined by two new faces at SwanseaCon, Sallyann Freudenberg and Seb Rose. Sallyann will be giving an opening Keynote on day two with Seb bringing the event to a close on day two with the the closing keynote to SwanseaCon 2017. SwanseaCon is very lucky in having these exceptional speakers give their time to share their thoughts and knowledge with the community and we hope you will be as excited as us to see them at the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sander Hoogendoorn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sander is an independent dad, mentor, trainer, software architect, programmer, speaker, and writer. He is a highly appreciated catalyst in the innovation of software development at his many international clients. Well known as the author of the best-selling book This Is Agile, Sander coaches organizations, projects and teams, has written books on UML and agile, and published over 250 articles in international magazines. He is an inspiring (keynote) speaker at many international conferences, and presents seminars and training courses on a variety of topics such as (beyond) agile, Scrum, Kanban, software estimation, software architecture, microservices, design patterns, modeling and UML, writing code, and testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sallyann Freudenberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With more than 25 years in the world of software development, Sal uniquely blends over ten years of doing, coaching and teaching Agile approaches with her research into the psychology of programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An experienced and popular speaker, most recently she has been speaking out to the tech industry on neurodiversity and how to support the different kinds of brains our industry needs. Her talks include keynotes at Oredev, RallyOn, and Lean Agile Scotland. She has also spoken several times at the XP20XX series of conferences in Europe, at QCON, London Lean Kanban Days, various European Scrum Gatherings, The symposium on Visual Languages and Human Centric Computing and the symposium on Cooperative Systems Design Conference (COOP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seb Rose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consultant, Designer, Analyst and Developer for over 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been involved in the full development lifecycle with experience that ranges from Architecture to Support, from BASIC to Ruby. Recently I have been helping teams adopt and refine their agile practices, with a particular focus on automated testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regular speaker at conferences and occasional contributor to software journals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributing author to ‘‘97 Things Every Programmer Should Know’’ - O’Reilly. Lead author of ‘‘The Cucumber for Java Book’’ - Pragmatic Programmers (2015)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details about speakers, agenda and tickets will appear in subsequent posts. In the meantime like us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/swanseacon&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, follow on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SwanseaCon&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, add to circles in &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/u/1/105624973822199981487&quot;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; or subcribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;//swancon.us10.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=6f529863589ed3eabebff1faf&amp;amp;id=ac260fb163&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; in order not to miss any cool stuff about the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/keynote-speakers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/keynote-speakers</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for papers is now closed</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The call for speakers for our third event has now closed. The response has been fantastic, over 120 submissions were received from speakers all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re are currently busy putting together an agenda for the third Agile Development &amp;amp; Software Craftsmanship conference in Wales - &lt;a href=&quot;http://swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;SwanseaCon 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What to expect:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attendance&lt;/strong&gt;: we’re expecting over 200 attendees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic&lt;/strong&gt;: more than 25 hours of agile development &amp;amp; software craftsmanship&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: 25-26 of September, expect a two day event&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue&lt;/strong&gt;: Liberty Stadium, Swansea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speakers&lt;/strong&gt;: more than 25 world class speakers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details about speakers, agenda and tickets will appear in subsequent posts. In the meantime like us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/swanseacon&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, follow on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SwanseaCon&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, add to circles in &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/u/1/105624973822199981487&quot;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; or subcribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;//swancon.us10.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=6f529863589ed3eabebff1faf&amp;amp;id=ac260fb163&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; in order not to miss any cool stuff about the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/call-for-papers-now-closed</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/call-for-papers-now-closed</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Awesome Employers list</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;awesome-employers-list&quot;&gt;Awesome Employers list.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we will be doing an Awesome Employers list so please let your boss and their boss know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your company sends 5 or more staff (or all IT if &amp;lt; 5) to SwanseaCon 2017, they’ll find themselves publicised for investing in staff and will have their logo on the website as an awesome employer, they will also receive a small discount of 15% off tickets. For any organisation, this means a free reputation boost locally!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;swanseacon-2017&quot;&gt;SwanseaCon 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blind early bird tickets are currently on sale for SwanseaCon 2017. The speakers and schedule are yet to be announced which is why the tickets have been made available at a reduced cost but we hope to have a few of this years favourites return as well as lots of new attendees/speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk&quot;&gt;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 13:43:54 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/awesome-employers-list</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/awesome-employers-list</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Donation of notebooks to Pontybrenin Primary School</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;donation-of-notebooks-to-pontybrenin-primary-school&quot;&gt;Donation of notebooks to Pontybrenin Primary School.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back last year at the first Swanseacon, attendees were told that profits made from SwanseaCon 2015 would go toward helping provide free netbooks for children, which they would then use to learn to code at a free summer code camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August 2015, 10 netbooks were purchased and the idea was to have a day of coding with children and afterwards the children would get to keep the computers to continue their learning. SwanseaCon is run by myself (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/11vlr&quot;&gt;@11vlr&lt;/a&gt;) and as well as the conference I teach &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/CodeClub&quot;&gt;@CodeClub&lt;/a&gt; once a week at a local school (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/GorseinonPS&quot;&gt;@GorseinonPS&lt;/a&gt;) and am also heavily involved in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/IgniteSwansea&quot;&gt;@IgniteSwansea&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/SwanseaSDC&quot;&gt;@SwanseaSDC&lt;/a&gt; so as you can imagine my time can be stretched quite a bit at times and I struggled to arrange the coding day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the fact that I already help children code and wanting to help as many children get in to coding as possible I decided that perhaps the best approach would be to donate the computers to a local school, potentially helping a lot more than the 10 children I initially hoped to help. Ahead of our second year in August 2016, I was made aware by a &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/MrMarkProbez&quot;&gt;work colleague&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/Pontybrenin&quot;&gt;Pontybrenin Primary School&lt;/a&gt; were trying to raise funds to get computers for the children. I was amazed to find out they didn’t have any at all and so this was an easy decision! &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/11vlr/status/783660042671226882&quot;&gt;Yesterday the 10 notebook computers were handed over!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank you!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank both &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/simonbrown&quot;&gt;Simon Brown&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jiriknesl&quot;&gt;Jiri Knesl&lt;/a&gt; for both support and financial assistance to help make this happen as well as the fantastic support from attendees and sponsors for the last two years - none of this would have been possible without you all so thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just the smallest of things like donating the netbooks will make a massive difference to help the school and children as well as helping the wider goal of trying to build and foster a great tech community in South Wales, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks again for your support,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Viv&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;swanseacon-2017&quot;&gt;SwanseaCon 2017&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blind early bird tickets are currently on sale for SwanseaCon 2017. The speakers and schedule are yet to be announced which is why the tickets have been made available at a reduced cost but we hope to have a few of this years favourites return as well as lots of new attendees/speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk&quot;&gt;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 07:15:10 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/donating-notebooks-from-swanseacon</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/donating-notebooks-from-swanseacon</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for speakers is now closed</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;call-for-speakers-is-now-closed&quot;&gt;Call for speakers is now closed.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The response to our call for speakers has been amazing, we received over 100 submissions from all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first conference in 2015 saw 2 keynotes, over 20 presentations and a panel discussion. This year we’ve tried to offer even greater value for money and to give attendees an even better opportunity to learn and share knowledge. There will be an opening and closing keynote by Simon Brown and Sander Hoogendoorn as well as two different tracks containing tutorials, hands on sessions, as well as presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SwanseaCon 2016 is aimed at software developers, software architects, project managers, analysts and consultants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event will have a strong practical focus on agile development, software craftsmanship, teams and business, to ensure participants have the opportunity to learn new approaches they can immediately apply in their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;earl-bird-tickets&quot;&gt;Earl bird tickets&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still have early bird tickets on sale until the end of March which offers you £200 off a standard ticket. Tickets include access to both days (Monday 12th- Tuesday 13th), breakfast, lunch, tea/coffee, and access to the evening reception on Monday 12th September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t miss out on the chance to snap up a ticket for possibly the cheapest agile and developer conference you’ll attend this year. Once the early bird tickets are gone or the deadline passes that’s it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-more-advice-or-information&quot;&gt;For more advice or information&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hello@swanseacon.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;07722 328 233&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;twitter.com/SwanseaCon&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 20:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/call-for-speakers-now-closed</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/call-for-speakers-now-closed</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for speakers is now open</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;call-for-speakers-is-now-open&quot;&gt;Call for speakers is now open.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re really pleased to announce that after a really successful first conference we’re going to do it all over again 12-13th September, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SwanseaCon is aimed at software developers, software architects, project managers, analysts and consultants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event has a strong practical focus on agile development, software craftsmanship, teams and business, to ensure participants have the opportunity to learn new approaches they can immediately apply in their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of our previous attendees have held the following positions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Senior Consultant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software Craftsman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lead Software Engineer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Professor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Entrepreneur&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apprentice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trainer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delivery Director&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software Architect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Services Engineer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scrum Master&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Director of Digital Services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blogger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;sessions&quot;&gt;Sessions&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re happy for you to stand up and present a talk about your experiences or something you’ve done, but we also strongly encourage interactive sessions that generate conversation with the audience, group discussion, or hands-on experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no limit to the number of sessions you can submit. Upon submission you will need to select a category which loosely describes your session; presentation, tutorial (includes some group activities), hands-on (practical session - on laptops etc), panel discussion or if your unsure you can enter your own. You will also be able to select how long in length your session will be, we may however have to ask you to vary your session length so it fits into our finished programme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;speaker-support&quot;&gt;Speaker support&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s included&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 nights hotel stay (night before your session/night after)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Participation in the full event programme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lunch on each day you attend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Refreshments with delegates at designated times&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free wi-fi at the conference venue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delegate pack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything not listed above is not included.
Contact us about any specific requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;expenses&quot;&gt;Expenses&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although our general policy is not to cover speaker expenses we do have some money to help speakers who are personally funding their own way to SwanseaCon - we would strongly prefer to direct this money to those who most need this support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll provide flip charts, pens, a/v equiptment etc. but we can also help fund anything out of the ordinary you need to make your session more valuable to your participants and yourelf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let us know on your session proposal whether you need this support to take part in the conference, and, if possible, roughly how much money you’d need to claim from us. (To give you a rough idea, overnight accomodation in the city costs from £79 upwards per night).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we can’t reimburse expenses that we haven’t agreed to pay in advance of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;session-reviews&quot;&gt;Session reviews&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the deadline closes, our selection panel will review all submissions anonymously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The review process usually takes between 2 and 3 weeks depending on the volume of submissions. We’ll contact both successful and unsuccessful candidates within the review period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re ready to submit a session for consideration, please visit:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/call-for-speakers&quot;&gt;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/call-for-speakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-more-advice-or-information&quot;&gt;For more advice or information&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re happy to provide further advice if you need more help before submitting your session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hello@swanseacon.co.uk/call-for-speakers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;07722 328 233&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;twitter.com/SwanseaCon&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 14:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/call-for-speakers-now-open</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/call-for-speakers-now-open</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thank you for attending SwanseaCon 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;prynhawn-dagood-afternoon&quot;&gt;Prynhawn da/Good afternoon,&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really hope you enjoyed SwanseaCon 2015 and we just wanted to write a quick post to say a massive thank you for coming along and being a part of it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feedback so far has been excellent and we’re already looking at ways to implement some of the suggestions. If you didn’t get a chance to leave feedback we’d love to know your thoughts so please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hello@swanseacon.co.uk?feedback&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had lots of photographs of both days taken, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/136328291@N04&quot;&gt;click here to view photos from SwanseaCon 2015&lt;/a&gt;. We recorded nearly all the speaker sessions so we will let you know as soon as these are available online for you to take a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers have already started posting links to their slides which you can find below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codingthearchitecture.com/presentations/swanseacon2015-software-architecture-vs-code&quot;&gt;Simon Brown - Software architecture vs code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/christosmatskas/common-mistakes-in-tdd-can-you-guess&quot;&gt;Christos Matskas - Common mistakes in tdd can you guess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/marcello.duarte/understanding-craftsmanship-swanseacon2015-52546920&quot;&gt;Marcello Duarte - Understanding Craftsmanship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/RachelDavies/swanseacon-closing-keynote&quot;&gt;Rachel Davies - Swanseacon Closing Keynote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://talks.samirtalwar.com/use-your-type-system.html&quot;&gt;Samir Talwar - Use Your Type System; Write Less Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/valtechuk/leanux-and-agile-in-the-public-sector&quot;&gt;Kevin Murray - LeanUX and Agile in the Public Sector&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slides.com/franziskasauerwein/refactoring#/&quot;&gt;Erik Talboom &amp;amp; Franzi SauerWein - Refactoring mount doom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codemanship.co.uk/files/ContinuousInspection.pdf&quot;&gt;Jason Gorman - Continous Inspection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/tooky/surrender-the-illusion-of-control&quot;&gt;Steve Tooke - Surrender the Illusion of Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/adibolb/legacy-code-is-fear-swanseacon-08-09-2015&quot;&gt;Adrian Bolboaca - Legacy Code is Fear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/aahoogendoorn/microservices-stairway-to-heaven-or-highway-to-hell&quot;&gt;Sander Hoogendoorn - Designing and building a micro-services architecture. Stairway to heaven or a highway to hell?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you once again for being a part of our first conference, we’re already planning next year’s event which will run Monday 12th - Tuesday 13th September 2016. Super early bird tickets are available now, enabling all this years attendees to come along for just £125!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope to see you next year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diolch/Thank you,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SwanseaCon team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get all the latest news and updates about next years conference over on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/swanseacon&quot;&gt;our twitter account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 14:43:18 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/thank-you-for-attending-swaneacon-2015</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/thank-you-for-attending-swaneacon-2015</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Patroklos Papapetrou - Managing global teams</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;managing-global-teams&quot;&gt;Managing global teams.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year ago I took the most challenging decision of my software development career. I quit my daily - 40hr/week job and joined a company as a remote freelancer. That change was even more radical because I made the switch from a hands-on developer role to a “software engineering manager” role. Although I don’t like the term “engineer” for software development, that’s my current role/job description. My key responsibilities are around managing many development teams by focusing on automation and quality. What’s really awesome and at the same time extremely challenging is that all team members are located in every possible place around the world.&lt;br /&gt;
In this post I will share my so far personal experience and some things I learned the hard way when it comes to manage global teams.
Let’s face the truth. Remote working is an increasing trend for several startups and ‘traditional’ companies. Personally I think that in the near future more and more companies will switch to this new model of recruiting. Hiring people globally decreases costs but it hides a lot of risks and difficulties, especially when it comes to manage all those remote workers. Here are some of the most important challenges I faced:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;different-cultures&quot;&gt;Different cultures&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything I knew - or I believed I knew - about human relationships and the way that people handle common situations in a software development team collapsed from one day to another. You don’t know how people react when they hear something that you consider normal but to their ears doesn’t look the same way. The fact that you don’t speak your mother-tongue make things even more fragile. Words have different meaning in some languages and many phrases are not fully understood. To be honest, in the beginning I struggled a lot! After some time I found out that one of the keys to overcome this problem is politeness and clearness. Whatever you want to say, try to be polite, calm, confident about the message you want to pass and as much as clear you can.  It’s very likely that even if people are somehow offended from what you said, their reaction will be less hostile and they will be more willing to cooperate. You want also people to understand the full details - not just the general idea. We don’t write software by understanding the general requirements, right? We need the details!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;absence-of-face-to-face-communication&quot;&gt;Absence of face-to-face communication&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest problems I faced, especially in the beginning, was the fact there was no direct communication, no face-to-face meetings with the team members. How the heck was I supposed to manage all those guys? Fortunately the answer was in front of my eyes and I quickly realized that you can perfectly replace real meetings with virtual meetings. All you have to do is use the proper software, have a very good internet connection - this is very important for video calls - and finally setup periodical meetings. Daily meetings to catch current activities and remove possible roadblocks, weekly meetings for planning and demoing internally the progress and one meeting every month to demonstrate the status to stakeholders, product owners or whoever has interest on the product/project the team is working on. Yes, you are right, It seems to be a typical scrum meeting schedule with some adjustments. I made also very clear from the first day that everyone should attend the meetings, otherwise the team will not have the minimum level of communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;time-zones&quot;&gt;Time-zones&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the teams I manage is composed of a developer located in Latin America, another one in China and another one in India. And me, I’m somewhere in the middle - Europe! Things can ge get even more complicated if you consider the fact that some of these developers have a “daily” /office job that reduces their availability to certain hours. Like I said, I needed to setup daily and weekly meetings. No silver bullet here. When you work remotely you have to accept the fact that some meetings might not be during the typical working hours. It’s one of the prices you have to pay for getting the flexibility of a remote worker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;performance-evaluation&quot;&gt;Performance evaluation&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People, by nature, lose easily focus. It’s even worse when you work in your home instead of a typical workplace environment. To avoid such awkward situations and make sure that all team members are productive you need to set goals. Team goals and individual goals. Weekly, monthly and quarterly goals. Goals should be clear to everyone. But the most critical part here is that goals should be quantifiable and objective. The way you measure them is shared to all team members and it cannot be disputed by anyone. Then you will be able to rank your developers and maybe replace the worst one ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;collaboration-tools&quot;&gt;Collaboration Tools&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meetings are good to keep team members synced and focused on their goals. However they cannot completely replace work at office . It turned out that in order to allow people to collaborate - just like the do in the office - we need tools. Fortunately we have a plethora of them. To be honest the tools that we use in a typical working environment perfectly fit in distributed teams. Starting from the typical ones : Issue tracking system, wiki platforms, code review systems and…. chatting rooms. The choice of the correct chatting / collaboration tool will probably make the difference. What I strongly recommend is slack. The reason? You can do exactly what you can with traditional chat systems like skype, msn etc. and additionally you can integrate with numerous external systems like google docs, jira, jenkins, github just to mention a few. Cool features like channels and private chat rooms with full search capabilities make it even more attractive. After working with slack for more many months I can’t imagine my life without all these information that can be found in one single place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that was only the beginning and I could write a series of blogs for each challenge I faced or even a whole book - hey that’s a good idea! Who knows. Now that I’m a flexible remote worker I might find the time to write another book!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can listen to more from Patroklos this September at SwanseaCon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://swancon.co.uk/schedule/#session-5&quot;&gt;Managing global teams : Lessons learned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 21:43:18 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/patroklos-papapetrou-managing-global-teams</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/patroklos-papapetrou-managing-global-teams</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
