<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SwanseaCon 2018 - Agile Development &amp; Software Craftsmanship conference</title>
    <description>SwanseaCon is an agile development &amp; software craftsmanship conference</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Seb Rose</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-seb-rose&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Seb Rose.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/SebRose.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever your job title, you’re actually being paid to think!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?*&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books, conference talks, the internet are all awash with heuristics, patterns, models and acronyms to help us solve problems. They document how other people have overcome challenges in a way that makes those solutions accessible to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re not magic formulae. They help us think, but they don’t make thinking unnecessary. The ability to think is our ‘secret sauce’ and we need to start realising that, while experts have valuable things to say, we need to filter their insights through our own experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;35 years&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed it last year&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably…. but I haven’t looked yet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Seb Rose and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-seb-rose</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-seb-rose</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speakers: Oliver Gibson &amp; Monira Rhaimi</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speakers-oliver-gibson--monira-rhaimi&quot;&gt;Meet the Speakers: Oliver Gibson &amp;amp; Monira Rhaimi.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/OliMonira.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our session, we’ll discuss how an experimental approach to product development will lead to the many small failures that are essential to achieving great outcomes. We’ll share stories from our experience in startups and enterprises, the mistakes we made along the way and how we came to the realisation we needed to approach building products differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aim for you to leave knowing how to practically apply an experimental approach to your product development, how to create a culture of experimentation and to recognise the dangers of launching without learning first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We both started our careers as software developers and felt the pain of seeing projects we worked on not succeed even though they had great architectures, were well tested and
utilised the latest development frameworks. We were frustrated at being told what to build, but not why;disappointed that our customers rarely used what we built; and fed up with
seeing months, sometimes years, of hard work being written off as a mistake. We realised there must be a better way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now focus our time helping teams build the right things rather than investing their valuable time otherwise. From this work, we developed a repeatable pattern for quickly
prioritising and testing ideas; validating and measuring their potential; learning quickly and ensuring teams launch the right product. By applying this pattern, our teams have reduced the risk of building new products and features but are also free to independently define solutions that best solve the problems they face. We’ve found this approach also leads to more enjoyable and satisfying work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No specific prerequisites. Come in with curiosity and an open mind. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A combined 17 years :p&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is about failing and learning from it. And how fast you go through that loop. Once you realise this, it’s liberating, you can try anything and never fail, just learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be our first time at SwanseaCon and Monira’s first time in Wales! We’re very excited at the opportunity to share our talk as well as learning from all the other great speakers and attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conference was recommended to us by a colleague and we wanted to share what we have learned with an audience that was as passionate about their craft as we are, so
SwanseaCon made sense to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Culture for the win&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am here for an argument – Working with conflict in teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nature of Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything culture related sounds very exciting to learn more about as this is related to issues
we face quite a lot in our engagements. Every talk always has some gems within it and we’re
always looking to pick up new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Oliver Gibson, Monira Rhaimi and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-oliver-gibson-and-monira-rhaimi</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-oliver-gibson-and-monira-rhaimi</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Matt Fortunka</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-matt-fortunka&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Matt Fortunka.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/MatthewFortunka.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azure from A-Z&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things when learning a new technology or platform is what to google? The rate of change with cloud, and particularly Microsoft Azure makes knowing the foundations and what is available all the more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have been involved in shipping software solutions and appreciate the moving parts involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;over 20 years&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t know everything so focus on the basics and areas you enjoy and learn how to be good at googling for everything else&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope, first time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am proud to represent one of the sponsors this year, Confused.com, and hope to share some of our findings from 6 years in the cloud&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having heard both Hadi Hariri and Sander Hogendoorn speak a few years ago I am looking forward to hearing what they have to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Matt Fortunka and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-matt-fortunka</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-matt-fortunka</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Gem Hill</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-gem-hill&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Gem Hill.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/GemHill.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anxiety Under Test&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to get to a place where the tech industry specifically and humanity in general are more comfortable talking about mental health. It’s good for us and will help us be healthier, happier people. I also want to try to reassure people that are or have struggled with mental illness or ill-health that they’re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An open mind. I want to add here that there are no trigger/content warnings for this talk other than I will be talking about anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a tester for 5/6 years now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test community is the best! They’re so supportive in all aspects of my life and I’ve made some true friends there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No! I’m excited to be here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Wales, but haven’t really been to Swansea! The conference also looked good and has a good CoC, and isn’t Pay to Speak, which all makes me very happy to speak there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gosh. They all look great. I am excited about finally meeting Lisa Crispin, but I’m also looking forward to be surprised by a talk that I didn’t think was going to be for me, which tends to happen at all conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Gem Hill and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-gem-hill</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-gem-hill</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Shahid Iqbal</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-shahid-iqbal&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Shahid Iqbal.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/ShahidIqbal.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes for .NET developers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?*&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arguably Kubernetes has become the de facto container orchestration platform, however with its origins in firmly in the Linux world it can be a daunting subject for .NET developers who traditionally come from a Windows world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes also provides .NET developers an opportunity to utilise the same platform to deploy both traditional full .NET framework applications and also newer .NET Core applications, this is a journey many .NET shops will be embarking on as they modernise their software and a platform like Kubernetes can help make the transition easier by providing many capabilities that would otherwise need to be created by the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My talk tries to break down the barriers to entry for people by demonstrating how quickly you can get started with Kubernetes and once you have the basics you can go away and dig deeper into this amazing and comprehensive platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would help the audience if they have an understanding of what Containers are and how to create them, my talk will cover what you can do with containers once you’ve created them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 10yrs now as a .NET developer/Architect with the past 2 years as a freelance hands-on consultant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That there are only 2 hard things in computer science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Naming things&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cache invalidation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Off by one errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed being part of the inaugural DDD Wales and love talking about cool tech to as many people as possible, I’ve not spoken in Wales much so it’s an opportunity to meet more like minded people. I also particularly enjoy the atmosphere of smaller more intimate events where you can be a bit more relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure I can single out any specific sessions as the whole line-up looks great. It’s a shame I miss the sessions that are on at the same time as I am speaking!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Shahid Iqbal and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-shahid-iqbal</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-shahid-iqbal</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Nick Tune</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-nick-tune&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Nick Tune.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/NickTune.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be talking about strategic design, the design of sociotechnical systems - how we architect our software services and set up our teams to build and maintain those services so that the teams have high levels of autonomy and ownership while collectively working towards business goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk two years ago, and afterwards an IT manager came up to me and asked for my advice: “My department spent 6 months converting their monolith to microservices and now every piece of work is taking 3 times longer and the teams are constantly having meetings and arguing with each other. What should I do?” he said. I had no simple answer for him, unfortunately, but his problem is not uncommon. There are hundreds or thousands of ways we can model our services and teams, and if we make bad design choices, we will have high coupling between our services and our teams and our productivity will suffer dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that we try to apply simple best practices to complex sociotechnical systems ‘make everything a microservice’ or ‘let’s copy the Spotify model’. Instead, we should be looking to heuristics and patterns as a way to co-design and coevolve our teams and software services based on the unique set of technical, economical, and social factors found in our organisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we cannot design sociotechnical systems from the top-down or the bottom up. We need to combine knowledge of the business strategy with the realities of our technical implementation to find the optimal compromise, and that means sociotechnical design requires input from developers up to management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever been blocked from delivering a new feature because you depended on another team who had higher priorities than helping you, or you’ve spent days of your life in meetings unproductively trying to agree with other teams about how a new initiative would be delivered, you’ll understand this talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first got paid to code between 9 and 10 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work on your personal relationships. Be someone that people can trust and feel comfortable to share their ideas with. It doesn’t matter how great your ideas are and whether you are right or wrong in a specific discussion, if people don’t feel comfortable working with you then as a team you will not achieve your potential and nor will you as an individual, and you’ll be a lot less happy. And if you do overstep the mark, be humble, say sorry, and try to repair trust as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-many-times-have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon&quot;&gt;How many times have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2018 will be my third year in succession of attending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-again-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon again this year?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I go to 10 - 20 conferences a year as a speaker or an attendee. Some of them are huge with thousands of attendees in all kinds of glamorous locations like San Diego, Amsterdam, and Oslo etc. But when the Swanseacon CFP opens each year, I get a unique feeling of excitement and anxiety. Swanseacon is one of a few events that I really want to attend and worry that I won’t get accepted at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you think I’m just saying this but it’s true and for a couple of reasons. Firstly, Swanseacon is an intimate event where speakers and attendees are close together. One minute you’ll be watching someone give a great talk, the next minute you’ll be sitting next to that speaker watching another person’s talk. I’ve met some interesting people at Swanseacon, speakers and attendees, who I still keep in touch with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I get a nostalgic feeling from the late summer sun in Swansea. I really don’t know why, but it captures my heart and feels timeless. Walking around the town with the warm sun, the feeling that winter is on the way, and with that seaside feeling, it puts my mind in a place that I don’t feel anywhere else and the glow lasts for a few days after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m running a workshop in Denver 2 days after Swanseacon. I should have flown to Denver a few days earlier to get over the jet lag, but there was no way I could miss Swanseacon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I’m not looking forward to my own. 10 minutes before my talk I’ll be sitting in the bathroom thinking “Oh my god, why the hell did I agree to give another talk in front of all of these people? Nick, you idiot!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I’m looking forward to some other talks but I’m also looking forward to being surprised by talks that didn’t stand out on the schedule but were absolutely brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, I will finally answer your question: I am looking forward to Stephen Mounsey’s talk: ‘I am here for an argument – Working with conflict in teams’. His talk last year was genuine and from the heart and captures many of the challenges I have faced as an individual trying to become a more positive and respectful person who works well with other people. Coincidentally, dealing with conflict in teams has been a theme for me this past year so I’m looking forward to Stephen’s talk for many reasons. Ironically, his was a talk that didn’t stand out to me last year when I looked at the schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Nick Tune and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-nick-tune</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-nick-tune</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Matt Jukes</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-matt-jukes&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Matt Jukes.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/MattJukes.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m talking about working, and thinking, in the open and how that helps us as individuals, teams and institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that openness is really the ‘secret sauce’ (well not that secret as it is open!) for this industry of ours. It is more than the open source software on which we are all reliant - it is about open culture, being open minded and importantly being willing to share the rough with the smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 years!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That I would still be doing this in 20 years time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I’d have fought harder to protect the web we lost https://anildash.com/2012/12/13/the_web_we_lost/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been supporting Mozilla, Wikipedia, Open Rights Group and others for a long time but I could and should have done more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nope&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swansea is one my my favourite places and I have been spending a lot of time there this year for work so it was a great opportunity to speak at an event I’ve only heard great things about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are too many sessions I like the look of to mention here but I’m very much looking forward to hearing from Gem Hill and Allie Brock in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Matt Jukes and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-matt-jukes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-matt-jukes</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Lisa Crispin</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-lisa-crispin&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Lisa Crispin.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/LisaCrispin.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re going to explore how to question requirements for each story, ways to elaborate and build shared understanding among the whole delivery team. Participants will get a chance to take a one-line user story and practice the types of questions that help the team discover the story’s value. We start by asking why. What’s the purpose of the story, what is the goal? How can we measure whether the story achieves that goal once it’s released to production? Who benefits from the story? There are several useful frameworks to help guide these conversations, we will try out a couple of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever been a “customer” needing software, you’ve experienced this: it’s hard to know what you want until you get your hands on the keyboard and try it! We humans have a tendency to ask for an implementation, rather than start with a specific, measurable goal and leave it up to the team to decide the best way to implement. If the whole team, including testers, developers, product owners, analysts, operations and others understands the purpose of each feature and each story that is part of that feature, we can save a lot of churn and wasted effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curiosity! This is about asking good questions. As Pete Walen has said, “QA” stands for “Question Asker”. Testers are especially good at thinking of questions that others don’t think of. But this is something everyone on the team can learn to do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisa started out her first programming job in 1982! She moved into testing in the early 1990s and joined her first Extreme Programming team in 2000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisa wishes she had realized what a great approach her team was using back in 1982. It anticipated the “agile” principles that would come out 20 years later, collaborating with everyone on the team and working directly with the customers. Instead, Lisa got sucked into the waterfall world. Waterfall can work fine if the teams follow good technical practices such as continuous integration and TDD. But, in today’s world, customers expect products that respond to change and they want new value delivered frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s our first year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisa heard so many people talking about it last year, she was keen to participate this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s one of those conferences where there are multiple sessions at the same time that all sound compelling. Lisa is keen to see Gem Hill’s “Anxiety under Test” talk. She’s a fan of both of Gem’s podcasts. Lisa also looks forward to Lisi’s report from her pair testing journey, that is so inspiring!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Lisa Crispin and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-lisa-crispin</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-lisa-crispin</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Hadi Hariri</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-hadi-hariri&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Hadi Hariri.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/HadiHariri.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amongst other things, it’s about the impact of information in our age&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-keynote-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your keynote topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I’ve witnessed many times the prejudices and biases that we all suffer from and how often we do not understand the impact of our own small actions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly three decades&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so much when I started, but in University, I wish I’d have paid more attention to Haskell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d heard great things about the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m very much interested in topics related to communication and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Hadi Hariri and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 22:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-hadi-hariri</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-hadi-hariri</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Dave Stokes</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-dave-stokes&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Dave Stokes.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/DaveStokes.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MySQL 8 Server Optimization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many folks run MySQL and the new version of MySQL has some big changes for the better. Hopefully my session will help uses exploit those new changes.  The new temporary file type and histograms will be a big win for many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully if they do not run MySQL they will know a little about relational databases.  For those that run MySQL I hope this will polish their knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first programming ex[erience was at Grossmont Community College in El Cajon CA (and I doubt any alumi will be joining me) in 1978.  Fortan on punch cards on a Digital Equipement Corporation KL 1091 36 bit computer.  And I started getting paid to work on computers not long after. And yes back then dinosaurs did roam the school parking lots which could prove very messy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is okay to say ‘I do not know; let me go explore’.  Too many feel guilty they do not know everything and do not admit they need to research.  Of course once you join the ranks of those of us who do know everything it makes you humble. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience is very sharp and it is always a joy to talk to a great audience.  That and Viv Richards keeps promissing to introduce me to Catherine Zeta-Jones when she comes to the conference.  Viv: Is she still planning on attending this year??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m here for the argument, How to build products people care about, and Questioning Requirements.  I generally recommend first time conferce attendees attend one session on a subject they know zero about to expand their horizons.  That is if there is a hole in your schedule where there are no must attend sessions and that is often hard to do at Swanseacon.  And if you have questions for any speaker, please ask – even if it is before/after their talk as all the presenters love to sahre their knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Dave Stokes and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 16:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-dave-stokes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-dave-stokes</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
