<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SwanseaCon 2018 - Agile Development &amp; Software Craftsmanship conference</title>
    <description>SwanseaCon is an agile development &amp; software craftsmanship conference</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Stephen Mounsey</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-stephen-mounsey&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Stephen Mounsey.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/StephenMounsey.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflict in Agile teams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because every one of us deals with conflict each day. We disagree on all sorts of stuff. Agile values collaboration and consensus decision making for that to work we need to be able to work with conflict and disagreement in our teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing special, a thirst for learning a bunch of tools for dealing with conflict&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 10 years&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep learning, all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have it is a great event, one of the highlights of my year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a tester speaking at events which broaden my spectrum of learning is a key goal for me. I want to speak at SwanseaCon because it’s an awesome event and I really want to go again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to many of the sessions, they are usually of a very high standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Stephen Mounsey and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-stephen-mounsey</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-stephen-mounsey</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Elisabeth Hocke</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-elisabeth-hocke&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Elisabeth Hocke.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/lisihocke.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning of this year, I started out on a testing tour. I had many pair testing sessions with many different testers from all over the world, as experiment whether this is a feasible way to level up my skills. I am happy to share my lessons learned on this journey as well as tips to go on your own adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?*&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that continuous learning and self-improvement is crucial in today’s ever changing world. Personally I really enjoy to increase my skills and ways how I can provide value. But how to succeed in getting better than yesterday, every day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having been the lone tester in the company for a long time, I always wondered where I stand regarding my knowledge and skills as a tester. I’m not the only tester anymore, but still I wanted to become better at assessing my own skills, and especially, improving them. Learning on my own is a feasible way and can lead me that far, but I struggle doing so with hands-on topics. I rather start new things without finishing them and miss the feedback whether I’m going in the right direction. Learning in a pair or mob situation, however, already proved very valuable to me so I got myself into situations to do so with other testers. Join my talk and learn whether the testing tour solved my problem of continuously improving my skills!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only prerequisite is to have an open mind. Although I will tell my story from a tester point of view, I strongly believe the lessons of my learning journey can be applied to many other roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fell into testing and agile in 2009 in a little startup building an AI middleware for game developers. I’ve come a bit around since then and saw different environments, taking over different hats, but always being a tester at heart and in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have loved to know that there is an amazing community out there with great people learning with and from each other that are so inspiring, supportive, and encouraging. Also, I wish I would have had the courage to reach out earlier than I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I had the honor to speak at SwanseaCon as well. It was a wonderful event with great people and I am really happy to have the opportunity to come back this year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference was really diverse last year when it came to the sessions. I really enjoyed listening to a variety of topics presented from different perspectives, all so relevant for development. Experience reports and personal learning stories are my favorite sessions and SwanseaCon provided plenty of those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolutely! This year it will get difficult as we have four tracks to choose from. I’m really curious to hear both the talks of Mashooq Badar about the “Nature of Learning” as well as Gem Hill about “Anxiety Under Test”; too bad they take place at the same time! Also, I’m looking forward to the workshop offered by Kristīne Corbus and Lisa Crispin: “Questioning requirements: improving quality for everyone”, practicing in a hands-on way to increase my skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Elisabeth Hocke and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-elisabeth-hocke</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-elisabeth-hocke</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Mashooq Badar</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-mashooq-badar&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Mashooq Badar.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/MashooqBadar.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nature of Learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning is a part of our survival and key to professional success. Understanding its nature helps us to become better learners. In our industry, where technologies and practices evolve so fast, effective learning is an absolute necessity. It is too important for us to simply stumble through, our approach to learning must be deliberate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None, or maybe an attentive ear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 Years&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critical Thinking and a deeper understanding of simplicity in Software Design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of my friends have attended and presented at SwanseaCon in the previous years. Their experiences have been amazing. I decided to experience it first hand myself this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am particularly interested in Sander Hoogendoorn’s talk “Do or don’t. There’s no try. Or is there?”, and  and Nick Tunes take on “Patterns and Heuristics”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Mashooq Badar and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-mashooq-badar</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-mashooq-badar</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Chris Cundill</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-chris-cundill&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Chris Cundill.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/ChrisCundill.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title of my talk is “releaseflow: a healthy build, release and deploy process”.  I’ll be using this opportunity to demonstrate a real, live example of Continuous Delivery which will be suitable for both newbies to CI/CD and to those who are hardened travellers down that road.  We’ll watch a code change make it’s way through a CI/CD pipeline all the way through to production live during the talk!  We’ll discuss how we can apply practices that facilitate continuous delivery in our everyday work.  We’ll also discuss the releaseflow.org branching strategy and why it’s superior to alternatives such as gitflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?*&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each software team desires to deliver value to their customers early and often.  The reality that teams face is often quite different.  This topic is important since we’ll identify what constitutes a healthy build, release and deploy process.  We’ll chat about changes that will get your team delivering more. We’ll expose the things that are toxic and must be addressed.  We’ll challenge the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-the-audience-should-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites the audience should have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be helpful if attendees for this session already work within a software development team in some capacity; whether that be in a supporting role such as Agile Coach, Business Analyst or Product Owner, or an active role such as Software Engineer, Ops or QA.  However, they’ll be something for everyone so feel free to come along even if you’re new to the industry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 14 years :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How awesome it was going to be!  Seriously, there’s so much to learn in this industry.  You’ll never have to lack motivation to get out of bed in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I spoke at the first two SwanseaCon events but didn’t manage to submit something last year due to time commitments.  The first year I gave an introduction to the Scala language.  The second year I performed a dual act with my friend Greg Simons for a talk entitled “Get your head in the Clouds”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of reasons; the first is that I wanted to speak about releaseflow.org and Continuous Delivery since it’s a subject I’ve been passionate about for years.  Second, I’m massively invested in the tech scene in Swansea and would love to see a rise in the innovation and craftsmanship of software here in my home town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely! It looks like a genuinely great lineup! Here’s a few I plan on attending:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“How to build products people care about” by Monira &amp;amp; Oli from Thoughtworks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“How to parse a file” by Matt Ellis from Jetbrains&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Testcontainers for Real Integration Tests” by Philip Krenn from Elastic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Chris Cundill and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-chris-cundill</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-chris-cundill</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Seb Rose</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-seb-rose&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Seb Rose.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/SebRose.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever your job title, you’re actually being paid to think!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?*&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books, conference talks, the internet are all awash with heuristics, patterns, models and acronyms to help us solve problems. They document how other people have overcome challenges in a way that makes those solutions accessible to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re not magic formulae. They help us think, but they don’t make thinking unnecessary. The ability to think is our ‘secret sauce’ and we need to start realising that, while experts have valuable things to say, we need to filter their insights through our own experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;35 years&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed it last year&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably…. but I haven’t looked yet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Seb Rose and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-seb-rose</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-seb-rose</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speakers: Oliver Gibson &amp; Monira Rhaimi</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speakers-oliver-gibson--monira-rhaimi&quot;&gt;Meet the Speakers: Oliver Gibson &amp;amp; Monira Rhaimi.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/OliMonira.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our session, we’ll discuss how an experimental approach to product development will lead to the many small failures that are essential to achieving great outcomes. We’ll share stories from our experience in startups and enterprises, the mistakes we made along the way and how we came to the realisation we needed to approach building products differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aim for you to leave knowing how to practically apply an experimental approach to your product development, how to create a culture of experimentation and to recognise the dangers of launching without learning first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We both started our careers as software developers and felt the pain of seeing projects we worked on not succeed even though they had great architectures, were well tested and
utilised the latest development frameworks. We were frustrated at being told what to build, but not why;disappointed that our customers rarely used what we built; and fed up with
seeing months, sometimes years, of hard work being written off as a mistake. We realised there must be a better way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now focus our time helping teams build the right things rather than investing their valuable time otherwise. From this work, we developed a repeatable pattern for quickly
prioritising and testing ideas; validating and measuring their potential; learning quickly and ensuring teams launch the right product. By applying this pattern, our teams have reduced the risk of building new products and features but are also free to independently define solutions that best solve the problems they face. We’ve found this approach also leads to more enjoyable and satisfying work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No specific prerequisites. Come in with curiosity and an open mind. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A combined 17 years :p&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is about failing and learning from it. And how fast you go through that loop. Once you realise this, it’s liberating, you can try anything and never fail, just learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be our first time at SwanseaCon and Monira’s first time in Wales! We’re very excited at the opportunity to share our talk as well as learning from all the other great speakers and attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conference was recommended to us by a colleague and we wanted to share what we have learned with an audience that was as passionate about their craft as we are, so
SwanseaCon made sense to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Culture for the win&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am here for an argument – Working with conflict in teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nature of Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything culture related sounds very exciting to learn more about as this is related to issues
we face quite a lot in our engagements. Every talk always has some gems within it and we’re
always looking to pick up new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Oliver Gibson, Monira Rhaimi and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-oliver-gibson-and-monira-rhaimi</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speakers-oliver-gibson-and-monira-rhaimi</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Matt Fortunka</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-matt-fortunka&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Matt Fortunka.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/MatthewFortunka.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azure from A-Z&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things when learning a new technology or platform is what to google? The rate of change with cloud, and particularly Microsoft Azure makes knowing the foundations and what is available all the more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have been involved in shipping software solutions and appreciate the moving parts involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;over 20 years&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t know everything so focus on the basics and areas you enjoy and learn how to be good at googling for everything else&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope, first time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am proud to represent one of the sponsors this year, Confused.com, and hope to share some of our findings from 6 years in the cloud&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having heard both Hadi Hariri and Sander Hogendoorn speak a few years ago I am looking forward to hearing what they have to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Matt Fortunka and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-matt-fortunka</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-matt-fortunka</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Gem Hill</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-gem-hill&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Gem Hill.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/GemHill.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anxiety Under Test&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to get to a place where the tech industry specifically and humanity in general are more comfortable talking about mental health. It’s good for us and will help us be healthier, happier people. I also want to try to reassure people that are or have struggled with mental illness or ill-health that they’re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An open mind. I want to add here that there are no trigger/content warnings for this talk other than I will be talking about anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a tester for 5/6 years now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test community is the best! They’re so supportive in all aspects of my life and I’ve made some true friends there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No! I’m excited to be here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Wales, but haven’t really been to Swansea! The conference also looked good and has a good CoC, and isn’t Pay to Speak, which all makes me very happy to speak there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gosh. They all look great. I am excited about finally meeting Lisa Crispin, but I’m also looking forward to be surprised by a talk that I didn’t think was going to be for me, which tends to happen at all conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Gem Hill and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-gem-hill</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-gem-hill</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Shahid Iqbal</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-shahid-iqbal&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Shahid Iqbal.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/ShahidIqbal.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes for .NET developers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?*&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arguably Kubernetes has become the de facto container orchestration platform, however with its origins in firmly in the Linux world it can be a daunting subject for .NET developers who traditionally come from a Windows world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes also provides .NET developers an opportunity to utilise the same platform to deploy both traditional full .NET framework applications and also newer .NET Core applications, this is a journey many .NET shops will be embarking on as they modernise their software and a platform like Kubernetes can help make the transition easier by providing many capabilities that would otherwise need to be created by the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My talk tries to break down the barriers to entry for people by demonstrating how quickly you can get started with Kubernetes and once you have the basics you can go away and dig deeper into this amazing and comprehensive platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would help the audience if they have an understanding of what Containers are and how to create them, my talk will cover what you can do with containers once you’ve created them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 10yrs now as a .NET developer/Architect with the past 2 years as a freelance hands-on consultant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That there are only 2 hard things in computer science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Naming things&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cache invalidation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Off by one errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon-before&quot;&gt;Have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon before?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon this year?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed being part of the inaugural DDD Wales and love talking about cool tech to as many people as possible, I’ve not spoken in Wales much so it’s an opportunity to meet more like minded people. I also particularly enjoy the atmosphere of smaller more intimate events where you can be a bit more relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure I can single out any specific sessions as the whole line-up looks great. It’s a shame I miss the sessions that are on at the same time as I am speaking!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Shahid Iqbal and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-shahid-iqbal</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-shahid-iqbal</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the Speaker: Nick Tune</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;meet-the-speaker-nick-tune&quot;&gt;Meet the Speaker: Nick Tune.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/NickTune.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-your-session-topic&quot;&gt;What’s your session topic?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be talking about strategic design, the design of sociotechnical systems - how we architect our software services and set up our teams to build and maintain those services so that the teams have high levels of autonomy and ownership while collectively working towards business goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-is-your-topic-important&quot;&gt;Why is your topic important?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk two years ago, and afterwards an IT manager came up to me and asked for my advice: “My department spent 6 months converting their monolith to microservices and now every piece of work is taking 3 times longer and the teams are constantly having meetings and arguing with each other. What should I do?” he said. I had no simple answer for him, unfortunately, but his problem is not uncommon. There are hundreds or thousands of ways we can model our services and teams, and if we make bad design choices, we will have high coupling between our services and our teams and our productivity will suffer dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that we try to apply simple best practices to complex sociotechnical systems ‘make everything a microservice’ or ‘let’s copy the Spotify model’. Instead, we should be looking to heuristics and patterns as a way to co-design and coevolve our teams and software services based on the unique set of technical, economical, and social factors found in our organisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we cannot design sociotechnical systems from the top-down or the bottom up. We need to combine knowledge of the business strategy with the realities of our technical implementation to find the optimal compromise, and that means sociotechnical design requires input from developers up to management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-prerequisites-should-the-audience-have-for-attending-your-session&quot;&gt;What are the prerequisites should the audience have for attending your session?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever been blocked from delivering a new feature because you depended on another team who had higher priorities than helping you, or you’ve spent days of your life in meetings unproductively trying to agree with other teams about how a new initiative would be delivered, you’ll understand this talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;How long have you been in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first got paid to code between 9 and 10 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-one-of-those-things-you-wish-you-knew-when-you-started-out-in-this-industry&quot;&gt;What is one of those things you wish you knew when you started out in this industry?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work on your personal relationships. Be someone that people can trust and feel comfortable to share their ideas with. It doesn’t matter how great your ideas are and whether you are right or wrong in a specific discussion, if people don’t feel comfortable working with you then as a team you will not achieve your potential and nor will you as an individual, and you’ll be a lot less happy. And if you do overstep the mark, be humble, say sorry, and try to repair trust as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-many-times-have-you-spoken-at-or-attended-swanseacon&quot;&gt;How many times have you spoken at or attended SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2018 will be my third year in succession of attending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-made-you-want-to-speak-at-swanseacon-again-this-year&quot;&gt;What made you want to speak at SwanseaCon again this year?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I go to 10 - 20 conferences a year as a speaker or an attendee. Some of them are huge with thousands of attendees in all kinds of glamorous locations like San Diego, Amsterdam, and Oslo etc. But when the Swanseacon CFP opens each year, I get a unique feeling of excitement and anxiety. Swanseacon is one of a few events that I really want to attend and worry that I won’t get accepted at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you think I’m just saying this but it’s true and for a couple of reasons. Firstly, Swanseacon is an intimate event where speakers and attendees are close together. One minute you’ll be watching someone give a great talk, the next minute you’ll be sitting next to that speaker watching another person’s talk. I’ve met some interesting people at Swanseacon, speakers and attendees, who I still keep in touch with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I get a nostalgic feeling from the late summer sun in Swansea. I really don’t know why, but it captures my heart and feels timeless. Walking around the town with the warm sun, the feeling that winter is on the way, and with that seaside feeling, it puts my mind in a place that I don’t feel anywhere else and the glow lasts for a few days after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m running a workshop in Denver 2 days after Swanseacon. I should have flown to Denver a few days earlier to get over the jet lag, but there was no way I could miss Swanseacon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-there-any-sessions-other-than-your-own-which-you-are-looking-forward-to-at-swanseacon&quot;&gt;Are there any sessions other than your own which you are looking forward to at SwanseaCon?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I’m not looking forward to my own. 10 minutes before my talk I’ll be sitting in the bathroom thinking “Oh my god, why the hell did I agree to give another talk in front of all of these people? Nick, you idiot!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I’m looking forward to some other talks but I’m also looking forward to being surprised by talks that didn’t stand out on the schedule but were absolutely brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, I will finally answer your question: I am looking forward to Stephen Mounsey’s talk: ‘I am here for an argument – Working with conflict in teams’. His talk last year was genuine and from the heart and captures many of the challenges I have faced as an individual trying to become a more positive and respectful person who works well with other people. Coincidentally, dealing with conflict in teams has been a theme for me this past year so I’m looking forward to Stephen’s talk for many reasons. Ironically, his was a talk that didn’t stand out to me last year when I looked at the schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;did-you-enjoy-this-post&quot;&gt;Did you enjoy this post?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseacon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets today to see Nick Tune and many others at SwanseaCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-nick-tune</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/meet-the-speaker-nick-tune</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
